<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-12T14:57:58-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jordan Colburn</title><subtitle>Personal website for Jordan Colburn. Software Development, Music, Electronics, Photography and Videography.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Getting Started with Modular Synths</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/04/getting-started-with-modular/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Started with Modular Synths" /><published>2019-01-04T14:52:14-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-04T14:52:14-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/04/getting-started-with-modular</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/04/getting-started-with-modular/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2019/01/04/IMG_20190104_141614_tgO8EBa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small Modular Synth Setup&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 was finally the year I got into modular synths. It's been on my mind for a few years, but I never quite took the plunge. The initial investment always seemed too high and I didn't have a firm grasp of what I needed. Today I want to offer some tips about cost effective ways to get started in eurorack modular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Start small&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't get overwhelmed with money or options. Simply start with a case, power supply and one module. Tip top audio, Moog and arturia offer cost effective cases that you can grow into.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Make an effects box&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the breakthrough that finally let me dive in. You only need one module to start with and if you think about using your modular as effects, it's really easy to get started. A filter, reverb, delay or even analog bitcrusing like the bastl tromso are great ways to get started to process your existing synths/guitars and other sound sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Get a modulation source&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real power of modular lies in the ability to modulate parameters. A simple LFO, or a used sequencer like the arturia beatstep or keystep can be used to affect parameters on your chosen effects module. Tempo synced filter sweeps, reverb modulations or bitcrusing can provide really unique effects that you can tweak hands on and are hard to recreate in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. DIY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many modules are available as DIY kits. If you've done some soldering, it is an easy way to add more modules and you learn a lot throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Take your time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really explore each module and step along the way. For me, it has been a huge learning process and each new addition inspires different musical ideas and workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Grow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semi-modular synths and modules that can act as a single voice (like mutable instruments Plaits) are great ways to add a lot of functionality in a space/cost effective way. Once you have a few modules and do some research, you'll slowly begin to realize what additions you need to make to expand your sonic palette in a way that fits the music you're trying to make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">2018 was finally the year I got into modular synths. It's been on my mind for a few years, but I never quite took the plunge. The initial investment always seemed too high and I didn't have a firm grasp of what I needed. Today I want to offer some tips about cost effective ways to get started in eurorack modular. 1. Start small Don't get overwhelmed with money or options. Simply start with a case, power supply and one module. Tip top audio, Moog and arturia offer cost effective cases that you can grow into.&amp;nbsp; 2. Make an effects box This was the breakthrough that finally let me dive in. You only need one module to start with and if you think about using your modular as effects, it's really easy to get started. A filter, reverb, delay or even analog bitcrusing like the bastl tromso are great ways to get started to process your existing synths/guitars and other sound sources. 3. Get a modulation source The real power of modular lies in the ability to modulate parameters. A simple LFO, or a used sequencer like the arturia beatstep or keystep can be used to affect parameters on your chosen effects module. Tempo synced filter sweeps, reverb modulations or bitcrusing can provide really unique effects that you can tweak hands on and are hard to recreate in other ways. 4. DIY Many modules are available as DIY kits. If you've done some soldering, it is an easy way to add more modules and you learn a lot throughout the process. 5. Take your time Really explore each module and step along the way. For me, it has been a huge learning process and each new addition inspires different musical ideas and workflows. 6. Grow Semi-modular synths and modules that can act as a single voice (like mutable instruments Plaits) are great ways to add a lot of functionality in a space/cost effective way. Once you have a few modules and do some research, you'll slowly begin to realize what additions you need to make to expand your sonic palette in a way that fits the music you're trying to make. &amp;nbsp;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2019/01/04/IMG_20190104_141614_tgO8EBa.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mainstage Looping Templates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/23/mainstage-looping-templates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mainstage Looping Templates" /><published>2018-05-23T04:26:45-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T04:26:45-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/23/mainstage-looping-templates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/23/mainstage-looping-templates/">&lt;p&gt;Since my video tutorial series on live looping using mainstage got a lot of interest and follow up questions (&lt;a title=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fc0XEouT8ZM&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fc0XEouT8ZM&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fc0XEouT8ZM&lt;/a&gt;), I decided to offer a custom mainstage consulting option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For $100 I will make a custom template for your live looping performance style&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just let me know what instruments you are looking to perform with (guitar, midi keys, analog keys, vocals, etc.) and what audio interface/midi controllers you have and I will build you a custom Mainstage Template with all the routing, buttons, instruments and effects that you need&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the button below to place an order and add the details of what kind of template you want and I will contact you shortly with some follow up questions. Please email me at &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jordancolburn@gmail.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; with any questions or more detailed comments you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt; &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;WDDVZC8WBK7CE&quot; /&gt; &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_buynow_LG.gif&quot; alt=&quot;PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;disclaimer/guarantee:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%;&quot;&gt;I can only create within the context of what Mainstage allows. If you need some custom logic that Mainstage is not capable of, I will try to help find you a workaround. If you are not completely satisfied with your final template, I offer a 100% refund guarantee&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Since my video tutorial series on live looping using mainstage got a lot of interest and follow up questions (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fc0XEouT8ZM), I decided to offer a custom mainstage consulting option. For $100 I will make a custom template for your live looping performance style Just let me know what instruments you are looking to perform with (guitar, midi keys, analog keys, vocals, etc.) and what audio interface/midi controllers you have and I will build you a custom Mainstage Template with all the routing, buttons, instruments and effects that you need You can use the button below to place an order and add the details of what kind of template you want and I will contact you shortly with some follow up questions. Please email me at jordancolburn@gmail.com with any questions or more detailed comments you may have. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; disclaimer/guarantee: I can only create within the context of what Mainstage allows. If you need some custom logic that Mainstage is not capable of, I will try to help find you a workaround. If you are not completely satisfied with your final template, I offer a 100% refund guarantee</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adjusting Aftertouch on a Korg Triton LE</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/26/korg-triton-aftertouch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adjusting Aftertouch on a Korg Triton LE" /><published>2017-12-26T22:15:29-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-26T22:15:29-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/26/korg-triton-aftertouch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/26/korg-triton-aftertouch/">&lt;p&gt;This all started when I recently played a Dave Smith Pro 2 in a music store and found it to be incredibly expressive. Specifically, the aftertouch was amazing and allowed me to really dig in and accent notes in a more expressive way similar to what I might do on a guitar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2017/12/27/unnamed_1_72mfBCP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to stave off the gear lust and avoid getting another keyboard, I went home and tried to program some similar patches on my Korg Triton LE 61-key and found myself disapointed. Even after trying all of the after touch curves, it seems like it was basically just on/off and I had to dig in really really hard to make anything happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I found out that many keyboads have a small auxillary circuit board just managing aftertouch inside.&amp;nbsp;These instructions should work on a Korg Triton LE, but will probably work on regular tritons, karma, trinity and even keyboards from roland and other manufacturers, since I think many of the manufacturers used a smilar supplier for keyboards and aftertouch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Disclaimer: This simple tip assumes you have basic knowledge of electronics and repair. I am not liable for any injury to yourself or your equipment if you follow these tips and do not know what you are doing **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, first try all of the aftertouch curves in the global settings. If one of those works, Great! If not, you are in the same boat as me and likely need a hardware adjustment. First, remove all screws from the back of the keyboard and find the board underneath the buttons above the joystick. Mine has one potentiometer that can adjust the offset of the aftertouch signal. You can also see where another potentiometer can adjust the gain, but mine has been replaced by a resistor (probably at the factory in an attempt to save like 10 cents on the part).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2017/12/27/unnamed_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I had to prop my keyboard up vertically to make sure I could still pay some test notes and adjust the offset knob. Be careful since the keys are probably no longer attached to anything. Plug in power and headphones and find a sound with a decent aftertouch modulation routing (make sure it does something very noticable). I went to the init piano patch, reduced the filter halfway and used aftertouch to control the filter cutoff with very high intensity. This way the sound should brighten up smoothly as you dig into the aftertouch. Unfortunatly, with my bad aftertouch, it was still on/off with a dull sound and a super bright jumop as I dug in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2017/12/27/unnamed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I swept the offset potentiomenter trying notes until I found a set point that resulted in a smooth transition that would allow a lot of expressive playing. Now that you've found your sweet spot, close up the keyboard and enjoy playing it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This all started when I recently played a Dave Smith Pro 2 in a music store and found it to be incredibly expressive. Specifically, the aftertouch was amazing and allowed me to really dig in and accent notes in a more expressive way similar to what I might do on a guitar. In an attempt to stave off the gear lust and avoid getting another keyboard, I went home and tried to program some similar patches on my Korg Triton LE 61-key and found myself disapointed. Even after trying all of the after touch curves, it seems like it was basically just on/off and I had to dig in really really hard to make anything happen. So I found out that many keyboads have a small auxillary circuit board just managing aftertouch inside.&amp;nbsp;These instructions should work on a Korg Triton LE, but will probably work on regular tritons, karma, trinity and even keyboards from roland and other manufacturers, since I think many of the manufacturers used a smilar supplier for keyboards and aftertouch. ** Disclaimer: This simple tip assumes you have basic knowledge of electronics and repair. I am not liable for any injury to yourself or your equipment if you follow these tips and do not know what you are doing ** With that out of the way, first try all of the aftertouch curves in the global settings. If one of those works, Great! If not, you are in the same boat as me and likely need a hardware adjustment. First, remove all screws from the back of the keyboard and find the board underneath the buttons above the joystick. Mine has one potentiometer that can adjust the offset of the aftertouch signal. You can also see where another potentiometer can adjust the gain, but mine has been replaced by a resistor (probably at the factory in an attempt to save like 10 cents on the part). &amp;nbsp; Then, I had to prop my keyboard up vertically to make sure I could still pay some test notes and adjust the offset knob. Be careful since the keys are probably no longer attached to anything. Plug in power and headphones and find a sound with a decent aftertouch modulation routing (make sure it does something very noticable). I went to the init piano patch, reduced the filter halfway and used aftertouch to control the filter cutoff with very high intensity. This way the sound should brighten up smoothly as you dig into the aftertouch. Unfortunatly, with my bad aftertouch, it was still on/off with a dull sound and a super bright jumop as I dug in. So I swept the offset potentiomenter trying notes until I found a set point that resulted in a smooth transition that would allow a lot of expressive playing. Now that you've found your sweet spot, close up the keyboard and enjoy playing it! &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Restoring a Rhodes Instructor Model (FR-7055)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/restoring-rhodes-instructor-model/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Restoring a Rhodes Instructor Model (FR-7055)" /><published>2017-10-31T14:32:43-04:00</published><updated>2017-10-31T14:32:43-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/restoring-rhodes-instructor-model</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/31/restoring-rhodes-instructor-model/">&lt;h1&gt;Rhodes FR-7055&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently had the opportunity to aquire a Rhodes Instructor Piano for a pretty good price. I couldn't find much info about the model (FR-7055) online, but based on the components inside and &lt;a title=&quot;http://www.keyboardmag.com/gear/1183/more-than-simply-mki-vs-mkii/59218&quot; href=&quot;http://www.keyboardmag.com/gear/1183/more-than-simply-mki-vs-mkii/59218&quot;&gt;this article from keyboard magazine&lt;/a&gt;, It seems to basically be a mark I somewhere between 1970 and 1974ish.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got it for a good price, but the condition is pretty bad and a few keys don't work. One is due to a broken hammer, a few have bidle straps that have been chewed by a mouse and a few seem to be bad pickups or bad pickup wiring. I've already cleaned most of the grime off with some damp clothes and elbow greese and plan on updating this page with more info as I begin to fix some of the notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 658px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background: #F8F8F8; line-height: 0; margin-top: 40px; padding: 50.0% 0; text-align: center; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background: #F8F8F8; line-height: 0; margin-top: 40px; padding: 50.0% 0; text-align: center; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BazYn2HgcZB/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;So... I got another one to fix up. I have a problem. Anybody looking to buy a Rhodes?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by Jordan Colburn (@jordan_colburn) on Oct 28, 2017 at 12:08pm PDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot; defer=&quot;defer&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: #FFF; border: 0; border-radius: 3px; box-shadow: 0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width: 658px; padding: 0; width: calc(100% - 2px);&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 8px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;background: #F8F8F8; line-height: 0; margin-top: 40px; padding: 50.0% 0; text-align: center; width: 100%;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0 0 0; padding: 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; line-height: 17px; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Ba2D6WshK-o/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trying to convince @colburn_video that restoring old keyboards is just like fixer upper. Demo day. Lots of funny graffiti as this Rhodes used to be a student piano in a classroom. &quot;Thomas wuz here&quot;, apparently.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: #c9c8cd; font-family: Arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; line-height: 17px; margin-bottom: 0; margin-top: 8px; overflow: hidden; padding: 8px 0 7px; text-align: center; text-overflow: ellipsis; white-space: nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by Jordan Colburn (@jordan_colburn) on Oct 29, 2017 at 1:05pm PDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot; defer=&quot;defer&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Rhodes FR-7055 I recently had the opportunity to aquire a Rhodes Instructor Piano for a pretty good price. I couldn't find much info about the model (FR-7055) online, but based on the components inside and this article from keyboard magazine, It seems to basically be a mark I somewhere between 1970 and 1974ish.&amp;nbsp; I got it for a good price, but the condition is pretty bad and a few keys don't work. One is due to a broken hammer, a few have bidle straps that have been chewed by a mouse and a few seem to be bad pickups or bad pickup wiring. I've already cleaned most of the grime off with some damp clothes and elbow greese and plan on updating this page with more info as I begin to fix some of the notes. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; So... I got another one to fix up. I have a problem. Anybody looking to buy a Rhodes? A post shared by Jordan Colburn (@jordan_colburn) on Oct 28, 2017 at 12:08pm PDT &amp;nbsp; Trying to convince @colburn_video that restoring old keyboards is just like fixer upper. Demo day. Lots of funny graffiti as this Rhodes used to be a student piano in a classroom. &quot;Thomas wuz here&quot;, apparently. A post shared by Jordan Colburn (@jordan_colburn) on Oct 29, 2017 at 1:05pm PDT</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is StubHub’s Website Deceiving users?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/stubhub-shows-already-sold-tickets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is StubHub's Website Deceiving users?" /><published>2017-09-11T14:40:05-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-11T14:40:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/stubhub-shows-already-sold-tickets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/11/stubhub-shows-already-sold-tickets/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: An Ebay employee reached out to me on twitter and claimed to have lodged an internal complaint (Ebay is StubHub's parent company). They followed up in a public tweet: &quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;StubHub is continually testing features to improve the customer experience. We have heard your feedback and have turned off the sold testing&quot;. They also reached out in DM on twitter and said it was part of an AB feature test (which I saw in the code), and they turned it off. While I am pleased at the prompt response, I am still skeptical. An AB test could make it more manipulative and not less if it was used to only show the &quot;feature&quot; (as they call it) on events where it was less likely to be discovered. The Ebay employee could not tell me how they determined which users to show this nefarious &quot;feature&quot; to.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2: The code still seems to be there, they just have turned off the AB for the events I have checked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My College, the University of Louisville, has one of their biggest ever home football games coming up this Saturday at home against #3 ranked Clemson. So I decided to check out tickets on StubHub (way too late for anything reasonable as it turns out). It is obviously going to be a tough ticket to get, but the amount of traffic and tickets selling on stub hub struck me as weird (spoiler alert, it is). So I put on my nerd hat, opened chrome dev tools and got to investigating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;stubhub.com&quot; href=&quot;http://www.stubhub.com&quot;&gt;www.stubhub.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, when you open the page, you are presented with a list of tickets to purchase. Then, like clockwork, two of the options suddenly get marked as &quot;sold&quot;. This creates a sense of urgency, almost like any ticket could be bought at any time. You know the site must be busy since these tickets are going from &quot;available&quot; to &quot;sold&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2017/09/11/Louisville_Cardinals_vs_Clemson_Tigers_Football_09_16_2017_Ti_IIWjCmM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;362&quot; height=&quot;623&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... wait a minute. Isn't it weird that the two that sold don't match the price ordering of the rest of the list? Also isn't it weird that the tickets get marked sold very soon after you open the page, and it's always the tickets right at the top? And isn't it weird that tickets don't continue to sell at the same rate while you keep the page open? Yes, it's weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digging through their javascript code, I found a nice snippet that seems to answer all of these questions. For the nerds, the code is below and for the non-nerds, I'll summarize here. When you load a page they get a list of tickets that have already sold, then they make sure to only show you two that you haven't seen before, and to insert them in random places in the top of the list so that you are sure to see them, then they mark them as sold to create a false sense of urgency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, you can test this out by opening dev tools (press f12 in chrome), navigate to the &quot;Application&quot; tab and delete the value beside the typo'd key &quot;ugrency-message-{IDOFYOUREVENT}&quot;. In most cases this value will be one or two ids (the ids of the tickets that were already sold before you loaded the page). Then refresh the page and see that most likely the same two tickets will appear in a different order and then be marked as &quot;sold&quot;. There should be an &quot;ugrency-message&quot; for each event that you have visited (they may have this set so not all events do it, I really haven't checked much outside the one game I was interested in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2017/09/11/Developer_Tools_-_https___www.stubhub.com_louisville-football_XkhXCzp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;379&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story is that StubHub is misrepresenting ticket availability to manipulate consumers, so be aware of the false sense of urgency they want to create when you are buying tickets. I hope this post helps you be a better consumer, and I hope it makes its way to someone at StubHub so that they can stop this and any other deceptive practices they may currently be engaging in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CODE from stubhub's client side code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;        appendJustSoldListingsTo: function(listings) {
            var urgencyMessageListings = gc.urgencyMessageData ? gc.urgencyMessageData.listings : [],
                eventId = this.eventId,
                listingsLen = listings.length,
                zoneId = listings[0].zoneId,
                sessionListings;

            if (!globals.hideUrgencyMessage &amp;amp;&amp;amp; SH.mbox.justSoldEvent &amp;amp;&amp;amp; urgencyMessageListings &amp;amp;&amp;amp; urgencyMessageListings.length) {
                sessionListings = sessionStorage.getItem('ugrency-message-' + eventId);

                // filter out sold out listings which already showed last time
                if (sessionListings) {
                    sessionListings = sessionListings.split(',');

                    urgencyMessageListings = urgencyMessageListings.filter(function(soldOutListing) {
                        var listingId = soldOutListing.seats[0].listingId;
                        return !_.contains(sessionListings, String(listingId));
                    });
                }

                // make sure only two sold out listings
                if (urgencyMessageListings.length &amp;gt; 2) {
                    urgencyMessageListings.length = 2;
                }

                if (urgencyMessageListings.length) {
                    // update cache
                    sessionListings = [];
                    urgencyMessageListings.forEach(function(listing, index, umListings) {
                        umListings[index].isSoldOutListing = true;
                        umListings[index].zoneId = zoneId;
                        sessionListings.push(listing.seats[0].listingId);
                    });

                    // append listing
                    if (listingsLen &amp;gt;= 5) {
                        // insert sold out listing into random position from 2~5
                        listings.splice(parseInt(Math.random() * 4) + 1, 0, urgencyMessageListings[0]);

                        if (urgencyMessageListings.length === 2) {
                            listings.splice(parseInt(Math.random() * 5) + 1, 0, urgencyMessageListings[1]);
                        }
                    } else if (listingsLen &amp;gt; 0) {
                        // insert sold out listing into at the second listing
                        listings.splice(1, 0, urgencyMessageListings[0]);
                    }
                }
                sessionStorage.setItem('ugrency-message-' + eventId, sessionListings.join(','));
            }

            return listings;
        },&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Update: An Ebay employee reached out to me on twitter and claimed to have lodged an internal complaint (Ebay is StubHub's parent company). They followed up in a public tweet: &quot;StubHub is continually testing features to improve the customer experience. We have heard your feedback and have turned off the sold testing&quot;. They also reached out in DM on twitter and said it was part of an AB feature test (which I saw in the code), and they turned it off. While I am pleased at the prompt response, I am still skeptical. An AB test could make it more manipulative and not less if it was used to only show the &quot;feature&quot; (as they call it) on events where it was less likely to be discovered. The Ebay employee could not tell me how they determined which users to show this nefarious &quot;feature&quot; to. Update 2: The code still seems to be there, they just have turned off the AB for the events I have checked. &amp;nbsp; My College, the University of Louisville, has one of their biggest ever home football games coming up this Saturday at home against #3 ranked Clemson. So I decided to check out tickets on StubHub (way too late for anything reasonable as it turns out). It is obviously going to be a tough ticket to get, but the amount of traffic and tickets selling on stub hub struck me as weird (spoiler alert, it is). So I put on my nerd hat, opened chrome dev tools and got to investigating. www.stubhub.com First, when you open the page, you are presented with a list of tickets to purchase. Then, like clockwork, two of the options suddenly get marked as &quot;sold&quot;. This creates a sense of urgency, almost like any ticket could be bought at any time. You know the site must be busy since these tickets are going from &quot;available&quot; to &quot;sold&quot;. &amp;nbsp; Well... wait a minute. Isn't it weird that the two that sold don't match the price ordering of the rest of the list? Also isn't it weird that the tickets get marked sold very soon after you open the page, and it's always the tickets right at the top? And isn't it weird that tickets don't continue to sell at the same rate while you keep the page open? Yes, it's weird. Digging through their javascript code, I found a nice snippet that seems to answer all of these questions. For the nerds, the code is below and for the non-nerds, I'll summarize here. When you load a page they get a list of tickets that have already sold, then they make sure to only show you two that you haven't seen before, and to insert them in random places in the top of the list so that you are sure to see them, then they mark them as sold to create a false sense of urgency. In fact, you can test this out by opening dev tools (press f12 in chrome), navigate to the &quot;Application&quot; tab and delete the value beside the typo'd key &quot;ugrency-message-{IDOFYOUREVENT}&quot;. In most cases this value will be one or two ids (the ids of the tickets that were already sold before you loaded the page). Then refresh the page and see that most likely the same two tickets will appear in a different order and then be marked as &quot;sold&quot;. There should be an &quot;ugrency-message&quot; for each event that you have visited (they may have this set so not all events do it, I really haven't checked much outside the one game I was interested in). &amp;nbsp; The moral of the story is that StubHub is misrepresenting ticket availability to manipulate consumers, so be aware of the false sense of urgency they want to create when you are buying tickets. I hope this post helps you be a better consumer, and I hope it makes its way to someone at StubHub so that they can stop this and any other deceptive practices they may currently be engaging in. CODE from stubhub's client side code: &amp;nbsp; appendJustSoldListingsTo: function(listings) { var urgencyMessageListings = gc.urgencyMessageData ? gc.urgencyMessageData.listings : [], eventId = this.eventId, listingsLen = listings.length, zoneId = listings[0].zoneId, sessionListings; if (!globals.hideUrgencyMessage &amp;amp;&amp;amp; SH.mbox.justSoldEvent &amp;amp;&amp;amp; urgencyMessageListings &amp;amp;&amp;amp; urgencyMessageListings.length) { sessionListings = sessionStorage.getItem('ugrency-message-' + eventId); // filter out sold out listings which already showed last time if (sessionListings) { sessionListings = sessionListings.split(','); urgencyMessageListings = urgencyMessageListings.filter(function(soldOutListing) { var listingId = soldOutListing.seats[0].listingId; return !_.contains(sessionListings, String(listingId)); }); } // make sure only two sold out listings if (urgencyMessageListings.length &amp;gt; 2) { urgencyMessageListings.length = 2; } if (urgencyMessageListings.length) { // update cache sessionListings = []; urgencyMessageListings.forEach(function(listing, index, umListings) { umListings[index].isSoldOutListing = true; umListings[index].zoneId = zoneId; sessionListings.push(listing.seats[0].listingId); }); // append listing if (listingsLen &amp;gt;= 5) { // insert sold out listing into random position from 2~5 listings.splice(parseInt(Math.random() * 4) + 1, 0, urgencyMessageListings[0]); if (urgencyMessageListings.length === 2) { listings.splice(parseInt(Math.random() * 5) + 1, 0, urgencyMessageListings[1]); } } else if (listingsLen &amp;gt; 0) { // insert sold out listing into at the second listing listings.splice(1, 0, urgencyMessageListings[0]); } } sessionStorage.setItem('ugrency-message-' + eventId, sessionListings.join(',')); } return listings; },</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Docker and Now to Deploy a Simple App</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/deploying-with-docker-and-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Docker and Now to Deploy a Simple App" /><published>2017-03-15T13:00:37-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-15T13:00:37-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/deploying-with-docker-and-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/15/deploying-with-docker-and-now/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bracketflip.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bracketflip.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To preface this: I am from the college basketball-crazed state of Kentucky. So naturally, March Madness results in a lot of time spent filling out brackets. Last year I wrote a small python script to simulate the tournament using a 50/50 coin flip, as well as a weighted coin flip that took a weight factor and slanted toward higher seeds based on that factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I wanted to take it a step further and turn my little script into a website anyone can use. Since I haven't spent much time with Docker, I decided to see how easy it was to deploy my python script in a container. First I modified my tournament class to return the results in a JSON format. Then, I used Flask (very lightweight server for python) to serve those results over network calls. Then I found a dockerfile to install python and my flask dependencies. For deployment, I used Now (&lt;a title=&quot;https://zeit.co/now#whats-now&quot; href=&quot;https://zeit.co/now#whats-now&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://zeit.co/now#whats-now&lt;/a&gt;). I had to tell docker to expose port 5000 (where flask was running) and then simply type 'now' in the command line and wait. Now generated a URL where my app was now live in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a front end, I wanted to save some time and just used an excel NCAA tournamenent template I found online and exported it to and HTML web page. I then added a very small angular controller to get the data from my python container when the user selected buttons. For displaying the results, I just used angular data binding inside the HTML table that excel created. Now also handles static sites as well as Node and Docker, so I was able to deploy my front end with now as well. Using docker alias, I then connected it to my custom url, bracketflip.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, with a little bit of effort, docker and now make a great pair to easily and quickly deploy small sites and web apps.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">bracketflip.com To preface this: I am from the college basketball-crazed state of Kentucky. So naturally, March Madness results in a lot of time spent filling out brackets. Last year I wrote a small python script to simulate the tournament using a 50/50 coin flip, as well as a weighted coin flip that took a weight factor and slanted toward higher seeds based on that factor. This year, I wanted to take it a step further and turn my little script into a website anyone can use. Since I haven't spent much time with Docker, I decided to see how easy it was to deploy my python script in a container. First I modified my tournament class to return the results in a JSON format. Then, I used Flask (very lightweight server for python) to serve those results over network calls. Then I found a dockerfile to install python and my flask dependencies. For deployment, I used Now (https://zeit.co/now#whats-now). I had to tell docker to expose port 5000 (where flask was running) and then simply type 'now' in the command line and wait. Now generated a URL where my app was now live in the cloud. For a front end, I wanted to save some time and just used an excel NCAA tournamenent template I found online and exported it to and HTML web page. I then added a very small angular controller to get the data from my python container when the user selected buttons. For displaying the results, I just used angular data binding inside the HTML table that excel created. Now also handles static sites as well as Node and Docker, so I was able to deploy my front end with now as well. Using docker alias, I then connected it to my custom url, bracketflip.com. All in all, with a little bit of effort, docker and now make a great pair to easily and quickly deploy small sites and web apps.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Teaching Code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/29/teaching-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaching Code" /><published>2016-08-29T10:48:45-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-29T10:48:45-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/08/29/teaching-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/08/29/teaching-code/">&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;I recently had the opportunity to tutor a kid from church in &quot;coding&quot;. Considering that software development was always something I learned myself or on the job, I wasn't sure how well I would be able to teach it, but I think I came up with a good approach that helped him learn a lot of a few 1 hour sessions this summer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;I wanted to keep the lessons fun, practical and helpful should he decide to dive deeper into programming later on (he's in 7th grade and has had some small programming experience in the past). I settled on teaching web development (HTML, CSS, and JS) to build simple websites and games.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;I mostly had a simple idea of a concrete task I wanted to get accomplished for the day (Make and publish a website, Add style and images to the website, Add a simple JS Game). And I would introduce any new concepts or languages, then dive right into creation. I tried to let him do all the typing and take his best guess at a solution or bug before offering some helpful hints.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;He was a quick learner and was able to follow along. Rather than teach the&amp;nbsp;intricacies&amp;nbsp;of all the tools we were using, I just wanted him to have a broad exposure to the IDE, command line, local servers, simple deployment scripts and version control in addition to understanding the code. He probably cannot recreate all the steps on his own, but he knows enough to go to google and solve his problems and he has seen/participated in all parts of development from debugging to deployment. My goal was to teach the practical and fun side rather than get bogged down in a lot of theory that on it's own might not have an application.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;If you ever find yourself needing to teach development, I highly recommend web technologies as they are very approachable (you can view HTML and type javascript right in developer tools). They also are very likely to be around in some form or another for the foreseeable future. It also makes it easy for your student to share and display the work they did with friends and family.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;*Special thanks to Lost Decade Games which had a really great simple game tutorial we based his game off of. After following the tutorial we were able to add simple features such as a timer, monster intelligence, smart borders, speeding up the game over time to make it harder and changing the images.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lostdecadegames.com/how-to-make-a-simple-html5-canvas-game/&quot;&gt;http://www.lostdecadegames.com/how-to-make-a-simple-html5-canvas-game/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently had the opportunity to tutor a kid from church in &quot;coding&quot;. Considering that software development was always something I learned myself or on the job, I wasn't sure how well I would be able to teach it, but I think I came up with a good approach that helped him learn a lot of a few 1 hour sessions this summer. &amp;nbsp; I wanted to keep the lessons fun, practical and helpful should he decide to dive deeper into programming later on (he's in 7th grade and has had some small programming experience in the past). I settled on teaching web development (HTML, CSS, and JS) to build simple websites and games. &amp;nbsp; I mostly had a simple idea of a concrete task I wanted to get accomplished for the day (Make and publish a website, Add style and images to the website, Add a simple JS Game). And I would introduce any new concepts or languages, then dive right into creation. I tried to let him do all the typing and take his best guess at a solution or bug before offering some helpful hints. &amp;nbsp; He was a quick learner and was able to follow along. Rather than teach the&amp;nbsp;intricacies&amp;nbsp;of all the tools we were using, I just wanted him to have a broad exposure to the IDE, command line, local servers, simple deployment scripts and version control in addition to understanding the code. He probably cannot recreate all the steps on his own, but he knows enough to go to google and solve his problems and he has seen/participated in all parts of development from debugging to deployment. My goal was to teach the practical and fun side rather than get bogged down in a lot of theory that on it's own might not have an application. &amp;nbsp; If you ever find yourself needing to teach development, I highly recommend web technologies as they are very approachable (you can view HTML and type javascript right in developer tools). They also are very likely to be around in some form or another for the foreseeable future. It also makes it easy for your student to share and display the work they did with friends and family. &amp;nbsp; *Special thanks to Lost Decade Games which had a really great simple game tutorial we based his game off of. After following the tutorial we were able to add simple features such as a timer, monster intelligence, smart borders, speeding up the game over time to make it harder and changing the images. &amp;nbsp; http://www.lostdecadegames.com/how-to-make-a-simple-html5-canvas-game/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixing Broken M-Audio AV40 Speakers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/02/28/fixing-maudio-av40-monitors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing Broken M-Audio AV40 Speakers" /><published>2016-02-28T16:34:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-28T16:34:17-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/02/28/fixing-maudio-av40-monitors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/02/28/fixing-maudio-av40-monitors/">&lt;p&gt;I recently aqquired a set of M-Audio AV-40 powered speakers that had died without warning on their previous owner. The power light still turned on, but only the right speaker played some crackling audio. A lot of online sources mentioned various capacitors that might need to be replaced, so I figured I would open it up and try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since none of the online guides totally solved my issue, I figured I would make this post to help out anyone else who may have my specific issue. My first problem was blown power supply filter capacitors similar to this blog post (&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.melissadunphy.com/2013/12/fixing-buzz-in-my-m-audio-av-40-speakers.html&quot;&gt;http://blog.melissadunphy.com/2013/12/fixing-buzz-in-my-m-audio-av-40-speakers.html&lt;/a&gt;). The replacements I picked up were much too large, so it took some creative jumper wires and configuration to get them to fit on the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2016/02/28/IMG_20160228_005218.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;447&quot; height=&quot;335&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After replacing the filter caps, the right speaker began working completely, but the left sounded fine when turned up, but was 20dB queiter than the right speaker (I troubleshooted by unplugging the right speaker). Some other posts led me to believe one of the multitude of 22uF capacitors was to blame. I tried replacing a few at a time and finally found the culprit in capacitor c13 as you can see highlighted in the picture above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacing this capacitor solved the riddle and now I have a pretty great portable set of studio monitors for free. They don't sound as clear or detailed as some of my larger Event and Mackie monitors, but for mobile tracking, they should be a big help!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently aqquired a set of M-Audio AV-40 powered speakers that had died without warning on their previous owner. The power light still turned on, but only the right speaker played some crackling audio. A lot of online sources mentioned various capacitors that might need to be replaced, so I figured I would open it up and try. Since none of the online guides totally solved my issue, I figured I would make this post to help out anyone else who may have my specific issue. My first problem was blown power supply filter capacitors similar to this blog post (http://blog.melissadunphy.com/2013/12/fixing-buzz-in-my-m-audio-av-40-speakers.html). The replacements I picked up were much too large, so it took some creative jumper wires and configuration to get them to fit on the board. After replacing the filter caps, the right speaker began working completely, but the left sounded fine when turned up, but was 20dB queiter than the right speaker (I troubleshooted by unplugging the right speaker). Some other posts led me to believe one of the multitude of 22uF capacitors was to blame. I tried replacing a few at a time and finally found the culprit in capacitor c13 as you can see highlighted in the picture above. Replacing this capacitor solved the riddle and now I have a pretty great portable set of studio monitors for free. They don't sound as clear or detailed as some of my larger Event and Mackie monitors, but for mobile tracking, they should be a big help!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Repairing an Ampeg V4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/12/03/repairing-ampeg-v4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Repairing an Ampeg V4" /><published>2015-12-03T09:19:38-05:00</published><updated>2015-12-03T09:19:38-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/12/03/repairing-ampeg-v4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/12/03/repairing-ampeg-v4/">&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;I was taking out the trash a few weeks ago and spotted an unlikely item by our dumpster. It turns out that someone had thrown away an Ampeg V4 tube guitar head (my wife now gets me to take out the trash by insinuating that I might find a matching cab)!&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2015/12/03/ampegv4-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;358&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2015/12/03/ampegv4-13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;357&quot; height=&quot;268&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;** Warning ** tube amps are very dangerous. Please do not mess around with them if you do not know what you are doing. Large capacitors can hold 100&amp;rsquo;s of volts even after the amp is turned off.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;I immediately went to test it out and it was predictably dead. My first thought was obviously to check the fuse, which tested good. I then did some googling and found a great resource in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ampegv4.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.ampegv4.com/&lt;/a&gt;. This showed me that there is also an internal 10A fuse on V4s. After opening up my amp, I found this fuse was blown. I replaced it with a hardwired short (no need to juggle 2 fuses in testing, although I replaced it with the proper value when I finished). I also made sure to properly ground the amp to prevent the possibility of shock (there are many tutorials you can find online about this, and on this amp involved removing the polarity switch from the circuit removing the infamous &amp;lsquo;death cap&amp;rsquo; and connecting the chassis to the ground plug on the power cable).&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2015/12/03/ampegv4-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;474&quot; height=&quot;356&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2015/12/03/ampegv4-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;473&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;Turning the amp on after this immediately blew the other fuse. So now I had to go searching for a different problem. Searching on the ampegv4.com website showed that a lot of amps have flyback protection diodes that often go bad and can keep an amp from starting. Looking at mine, they were bulging and it was obvious they had gone bad since they were bulging out like balloons. Since they are there for protection, the amp will run fine if they are removed from the circuit, which is what I did. The photo below shows the flyback diodes coming off the circuit board.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2015/12/03/ampegv4_nNyLjU7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;485&quot; height=&quot;364&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mce_filebrowser/2015/12/03/ampegv4-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;484&quot; height=&quot;363&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;After removing the flyback diodes, I was able to get the power light to come on. The tubes also glowed a bright, bright red (not good!) and you could hear a very queit crackling version of the input. The standby light also would not turn on, even when the amp was fully turned on.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;A few test points showed that my bias voltage was WAAAY off (actually swinging into positive instead of staying negative when standby was turned off). After testing some of the diodes, I was able to determine the bias diode (D6, you can see it marked in the middle of the circuit board photo above) was bad. I also could see that the resistor for the standby lamp (R54, on the left side of the photo and also fed from the same source as the bias voltage) was burned and bad as well. Replacing these two components was the key to getting the amp working again.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;During the troubleshooting process, I did a lot of general cleaning of the circuit boards and solder reflow as a general troubleshooting method hoping something would magically work. All of that was ok and didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt anything, but the most helpful troubleshooting technique was isolating my problem to specific parts of the circuit, testing components and replacing anything found to be bad.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot; standalone=&quot;no&quot;?--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-family: 'Helvetica Neue'; font-size: 14px;&quot;&gt;The Amp is now cleaned up and works great, although living in an apartment doesn&amp;rsquo;t give me many chances to really crank the volume like it deserves!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was taking out the trash a few weeks ago and spotted an unlikely item by our dumpster. It turns out that someone had thrown away an Ampeg V4 tube guitar head (my wife now gets me to take out the trash by insinuating that I might find a matching cab)! &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; ** Warning ** tube amps are very dangerous. Please do not mess around with them if you do not know what you are doing. Large capacitors can hold 100&amp;rsquo;s of volts even after the amp is turned off.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; I immediately went to test it out and it was predictably dead. My first thought was obviously to check the fuse, which tested good. I then did some googling and found a great resource in&amp;nbsp;http://www.ampegv4.com/. This showed me that there is also an internal 10A fuse on V4s. After opening up my amp, I found this fuse was blown. I replaced it with a hardwired short (no need to juggle 2 fuses in testing, although I replaced it with the proper value when I finished). I also made sure to properly ground the amp to prevent the possibility of shock (there are many tutorials you can find online about this, and on this amp involved removing the polarity switch from the circuit removing the infamous &amp;lsquo;death cap&amp;rsquo; and connecting the chassis to the ground plug on the power cable). &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Turning the amp on after this immediately blew the other fuse. So now I had to go searching for a different problem. Searching on the ampegv4.com website showed that a lot of amps have flyback protection diodes that often go bad and can keep an amp from starting. Looking at mine, they were bulging and it was obvious they had gone bad since they were bulging out like balloons. Since they are there for protection, the amp will run fine if they are removed from the circuit, which is what I did. The photo below shows the flyback diodes coming off the circuit board. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; After removing the flyback diodes, I was able to get the power light to come on. The tubes also glowed a bright, bright red (not good!) and you could hear a very queit crackling version of the input. The standby light also would not turn on, even when the amp was fully turned on. &amp;nbsp; A few test points showed that my bias voltage was WAAAY off (actually swinging into positive instead of staying negative when standby was turned off). After testing some of the diodes, I was able to determine the bias diode (D6, you can see it marked in the middle of the circuit board photo above) was bad. I also could see that the resistor for the standby lamp (R54, on the left side of the photo and also fed from the same source as the bias voltage) was burned and bad as well. Replacing these two components was the key to getting the amp working again. &amp;nbsp; During the troubleshooting process, I did a lot of general cleaning of the circuit boards and solder reflow as a general troubleshooting method hoping something would magically work. All of that was ok and didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt anything, but the most helpful troubleshooting technique was isolating my problem to specific parts of the circuit, testing components and replacing anything found to be bad. &amp;nbsp; The Amp is now cleaned up and works great, although living in an apartment doesn&amp;rsquo;t give me many chances to really crank the volume like it deserves!&amp;nbsp;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Live Looping in Mainstage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/31/live-looping-in-mainstage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Live Looping in Mainstage" /><published>2015-07-31T03:13:54-04:00</published><updated>2015-07-31T03:13:54-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/31/live-looping-in-mainstage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/31/live-looping-in-mainstage/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oVxLzfovwSY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;I now offer a service to create a custom looping template for your needs. For $100, I will work with you to build the perfect loops/routing/effects so you can focus on a great performance and not on googling mainstage setup tips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email jordancolburn@gmail.com for any questions or use the buy now below to place an order and send me your description of your ideal setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;form action=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;cmd&quot; value=&quot;_s-xclick&quot; /&gt; &lt;input type=&quot;hidden&quot; name=&quot;hosted_button_id&quot; value=&quot;WDDVZC8WBK7CE&quot; /&gt; &lt;input type=&quot;image&quot; name=&quot;submit&quot; src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/btn/btn_buynow_LG.gif&quot; alt=&quot;PayPal - The safer, easier way to pay online!&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.paypalobjects.com/en_US/i/scr/pixel.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/form&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/self-promotion&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;I have been been trying to find a good looping setup&amp;nbsp;for multi-instrumental live performance for a while. Usually I find a new tool (Boss RC20, Ableton w/ Launchpad, Ableton with pedalboard, Custom Looper in PD, Custom Looper in ChucK, you get the picture), get excited while setting it up, try a few songs and then move on to something else, but this time I think I found a solution that solves most of my problems using Apple's Mainstage and the Loopback plugin. First I want to explain the problems it solves for me, then I'll get to the details of how I implemented it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple Song Sections&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;- My current mainstage &quot;concert&quot; has 6 loopback channels. 3 of these are song sections (or groups in loopback terminology) A, B, C. This allows for automatic switching between sections such as verse, chorus and bridge. The other 3 loops are free to come in and out and can contain things such as drums or pads/drones so that I can bring drums in and out of songs to add more dynamics to a looping performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recall&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;- With Mainstage, I can save my guitar/key sounds directly with the concert and not have to remember which sounds go with which songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Routing Control&lt;/strong&gt; - Mainstage is a basically a giant mixer that can host plugins, so I'm free to route audio how I want. My main use for this is to have looper bypass for individual parts so that I can do things like play a multi&amp;nbsp;loop&amp;nbsp;solo on one keyboard while adding to the loop with another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Loop Quanitization&lt;/strong&gt; - By using a click (and tap tempo) I can have my loops quantized exactly the way I need them. Hitting record two beats before the loop kicks in really frees you up to think about the performance instead of trying to perfectly time all your button presses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Loopback Settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual looping plugin is called &quot;Loopback&quot;. I use pretty simple settings but I will attempt to explain them here. 3 of my loopers are set to separate groups A, B and C. This gives me three song sections to work with. When you are playing back one of the groups, and hit record or playback on a looper from another group, the first one will stop playing and the new one will begin. This is great because with one button press you can switch to a different song section. I have the loopers set sync to the click and &amp;nbsp;quantize to the bar. The length of the loopers needs to be turned all the way down so it displays '--' allowing you to set the length of the loop when recording it. All monitoring on the loops need to be turned off, otherwise you would hear your instruments on 6 different channels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Audio Routing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All looper tracks need to be created at the set level by clicking on the set in the left hand column. I have 6 looper track each with an individual Loopback plugin. These tracks have an input from a bus I call the 'looping bus' and their output to the main outputs. It helps to set up one track the way you want, test it, then copy it multiple times. I also have an aux track at the set level for each type of instrument I have (keys, guitar, drum pads, vocals). These all take inputs from separate buses and their&amp;nbsp;output feeds the main output. This is&amp;nbsp;how you monitor your playing. On these tracks, I also have a send setup at 0db to feed the 'looping bus'. This feeds your playing into the loopers. I have mapped multiple buttons to the mutes on these tracks allowing me prevent certain audio from going to the loopers. This way, I can be looping keys and guitar while a vocalist sings through mainstage without having her voice caught up in my looping. I can also unmute later to do things like add vocal harmonies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final step is to make the track with your actual instruments. I add a 'set' which looks like a folder to represent a song. Some instruments can go at the set level, while others will go in individual patches inside the set. For instance, If I only need one guitar sound the whole song, I would add it at the set level, but if I had multiple guitar sounds, I could make multiple patches with different sounds. Your input&amp;nbsp;for each instrument track will be whatever your input or midi controller is and add effects and instruments as needed. Your output will need to be set to the bus inputs on the aux tracks above to allow proper monitoring and loop bypassing. To stay on beat, I enable the click and pan it all the way to the right (after using the 'show click' option in mainstage). Then you can output the left side to the audio system/recorder (I'm currently using an interface with just 2 outs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Controller Setup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important controller mapping is loop record and playback. I have a foot pedal with 2 rows of 6&amp;nbsp;buttons on it. I set the top row to 'Record' on each of the six loopbacks and the bottom row to 'Play/Stop' (These mappings are found in the Loopback's 'Non-automatable' folder). This way, when Mainstage is playing back, tapping record will start loopback recording on the next downbeat. Tapping record again will set your loop endpoint, begin playback from the beginning,&amp;nbsp;and keep recording enabled allowing you to overdub. Tapping stop instead will do the same thing, but recording will be disabled. I also have buttons to reverse the loops and clear the loops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your button to clear the loops is also mapped to loop length, resetting it to '--'. I experienced a bug with this saved value being wrong, but deleting the mapping resetting the specific loopback instance to '--' length and remapping the button to length solved the issue for me. A 'clear all' button mapped to all the loops clear and length values is a nice addition too. Add in any other controllers you need for your instruments and audio effects and you should be good to go. Let me know if you have any other questions about my looping setup in Mainstage. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">&amp;nbsp; Update:&amp;nbsp;I now offer a service to create a custom looping template for your needs. For $100, I will work with you to build the perfect loops/routing/effects so you can focus on a great performance and not on googling mainstage setup tips. Email jordancolburn@gmail.com for any questions or use the buy now below to place an order and send me your description of your ideal setup. &amp;lt;/self-promotion&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;I have been been trying to find a good looping setup&amp;nbsp;for multi-instrumental live performance for a while. Usually I find a new tool (Boss RC20, Ableton w/ Launchpad, Ableton with pedalboard, Custom Looper in PD, Custom Looper in ChucK, you get the picture), get excited while setting it up, try a few songs and then move on to something else, but this time I think I found a solution that solves most of my problems using Apple's Mainstage and the Loopback plugin. First I want to explain the problems it solves for me, then I'll get to the details of how I implemented it. Multiple Song Sections&amp;nbsp;- My current mainstage &quot;concert&quot; has 6 loopback channels. 3 of these are song sections (or groups in loopback terminology) A, B, C. This allows for automatic switching between sections such as verse, chorus and bridge. The other 3 loops are free to come in and out and can contain things such as drums or pads/drones so that I can bring drums in and out of songs to add more dynamics to a looping performance. Recall&amp;nbsp;- With Mainstage, I can save my guitar/key sounds directly with the concert and not have to remember which sounds go with which songs. Routing Control - Mainstage is a basically a giant mixer that can host plugins, so I'm free to route audio how I want. My main use for this is to have looper bypass for individual parts so that I can do things like play a multi&amp;nbsp;loop&amp;nbsp;solo on one keyboard while adding to the loop with another. &amp;nbsp;Loop Quanitization - By using a click (and tap tempo) I can have my loops quantized exactly the way I need them. Hitting record two beats before the loop kicks in really frees you up to think about the performance instead of trying to perfectly time all your button presses. Loopback Settings The actual looping plugin is called &quot;Loopback&quot;. I use pretty simple settings but I will attempt to explain them here. 3 of my loopers are set to separate groups A, B and C. This gives me three song sections to work with. When you are playing back one of the groups, and hit record or playback on a looper from another group, the first one will stop playing and the new one will begin. This is great because with one button press you can switch to a different song section. I have the loopers set sync to the click and &amp;nbsp;quantize to the bar. The length of the loopers needs to be turned all the way down so it displays '--' allowing you to set the length of the loop when recording it. All monitoring on the loops need to be turned off, otherwise you would hear your instruments on 6 different channels. Audio Routing All looper tracks need to be created at the set level by clicking on the set in the left hand column. I have 6 looper track each with an individual Loopback plugin. These tracks have an input from a bus I call the 'looping bus' and their output to the main outputs. It helps to set up one track the way you want, test it, then copy it multiple times. I also have an aux track at the set level for each type of instrument I have (keys, guitar, drum pads, vocals). These all take inputs from separate buses and their&amp;nbsp;output feeds the main output. This is&amp;nbsp;how you monitor your playing. On these tracks, I also have a send setup at 0db to feed the 'looping bus'. This feeds your playing into the loopers. I have mapped multiple buttons to the mutes on these tracks allowing me prevent certain audio from going to the loopers. This way, I can be looping keys and guitar while a vocalist sings through mainstage without having her voice caught up in my looping. I can also unmute later to do things like add vocal harmonies. The final step is to make the track with your actual instruments. I add a 'set' which looks like a folder to represent a song. Some instruments can go at the set level, while others will go in individual patches inside the set. For instance, If I only need one guitar sound the whole song, I would add it at the set level, but if I had multiple guitar sounds, I could make multiple patches with different sounds. Your input&amp;nbsp;for each instrument track will be whatever your input or midi controller is and add effects and instruments as needed. Your output will need to be set to the bus inputs on the aux tracks above to allow proper monitoring and loop bypassing. To stay on beat, I enable the click and pan it all the way to the right (after using the 'show click' option in mainstage). Then you can output the left side to the audio system/recorder (I'm currently using an interface with just 2 outs). Controller Setup The most important controller mapping is loop record and playback. I have a foot pedal with 2 rows of 6&amp;nbsp;buttons on it. I set the top row to 'Record' on each of the six loopbacks and the bottom row to 'Play/Stop' (These mappings are found in the Loopback's 'Non-automatable' folder). This way, when Mainstage is playing back, tapping record will start loopback recording on the next downbeat. Tapping record again will set your loop endpoint, begin playback from the beginning,&amp;nbsp;and keep recording enabled allowing you to overdub. Tapping stop instead will do the same thing, but recording will be disabled. I also have buttons to reverse the loops and clear the loops. Make sure your button to clear the loops is also mapped to loop length, resetting it to '--'. I experienced a bug with this saved value being wrong, but deleting the mapping resetting the specific loopback instance to '--' length and remapping the button to length solved the issue for me. A 'clear all' button mapped to all the loops clear and length values is a nice addition too. Add in any other controllers you need for your instruments and audio effects and you should be good to go. Let me know if you have any other questions about my looping setup in Mainstage. &amp;nbsp;</summary></entry></feed>